[
   {
      "question":"At what age Mahavira attained ‘Kaivalya’?",
      "optionA":"37",
      "optionB":"40",
      "optionC":"42",
      "optionD":"44",
      "correctAns":"42"
   },
   {
      "question":"The core of Jaina doctrine is expressed in which of the following principles?AnekantavadaSyadavadaNayavadaPancha MahavrataSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1 & 2",
      "optionB":"Only 2 & 3",
      "optionC":"Only 1, 2 & 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2, 3 & 4",
      "correctAns":"1, 2, 3 & 4"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following are correct regarding Jatakas?",
      "optionA":"They are the stories of animals",
      "optionB":"They are the stories of Buddha’s family",
      "optionC":"They are the stories of previous births of the Buddha",
      "optionD":"None of the above",
      "correctAns":"They are the stories of previous births of the Buddha"
   },
   {
      "question":"With which of the following wandering ascetics Buddha practiced austerities?1. Kondanna2. Bhaddiya3. VappaSelect the correct option from the codes given below:",
      "optionA":"Only 1",
      "optionB":"Only 2",
      "optionC":"Only 3",
      "optionD":"1, 2 & 3",
      "correctAns":"1, 2 & 3"
   },
   {
      "question":"Who among the following was the president of the first Buddhist council?",
      "optionA":"Ananda",
      "optionB":"Nagasen",
      "optionC":"Ajatshatru",
      "optionD":"Mahakassapa",
      "correctAns":"Mahakassapa"
   },
   {
      "question":"Where was the capital of Shurasena located?",
      "optionA":"Saurashtra",
      "optionB":"Pooncha",
      "optionC":"Mathura",
      "optionD":"Potali",
      "correctAns":"Mathura"
   },
   {
      "question":"What were the rich peasants called in the 6th century BCE?",
      "optionA":"Gramabhojaka",
      "optionB":"Gahapati",
      "optionC":"Gramakas",
      "optionD":"Kammikas",
      "correctAns":"Gahapati"
   },
   {
      "question":"Bimbisara belonged to which of the following dynasties?",
      "optionA":"Mughal dynasty",
      "optionB":"Haryanka dynasty",
      "optionC":"Slave dynaty",
      "optionD":"Shishunaga dynasty",
      "correctAns":"Haryanka dynasty"
   },
   {
      "question":"Buddha died during the reign of which of the following kings?",
      "optionA":"Bimbisara",
      "optionB":"Ajatashatru",
      "optionC":"Udayin",
      "optionD":"Shishunaga",
      "correctAns":"Ajatashatru"
   },
   {
      "question":"Which of the following text mentions that the water touched by an untouchable is seen as unfit for consumption by higher caste?",
      "optionA":"Acharakkovai",
      "optionB":"Buddhacharita",
      "optionC":"Mahabhashya",
      "optionD":"Mrichakatika",
      "correctAns":"Acharakkovai"
   }
]